# AMOL MEHER

Address: Pune, Maharashtra India · Phone: 8177936318

Email: amolm497@gmail.com ·

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amol-meher-a99258157

Highly committed, performance-driven, seasoned IT professional with 4.8 years of experience in the industry and high-level proficiency in Core Java, Java8, Spring Boot, confluent Kafka, React JS, PostgreSQL. And have the knowledge of CI/CD Pipeline, GCP Cloud. Seeking for a position in a reputed organization to enhance my skills leading to organizational growth as well as professional well-being.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT**

#### **APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT ANALYST, ACCENTURE**

- Worked on stream microservices using Kafka API's and Kafka Stream API. Wrote producer and consumer API to publish and consume the data from topics respectively.
- Developed the new API endpoints based on the RESTful microservices. Also Developed and consumed JSON based RESTful services using Spring Boot and web flux. Also worked on to integrate new functionality to applications based on business requirements.
- Used Spring Boot framework to develop the controller and service classes for interacting with databases. Also used reactive Java programming features like Mono, Flux etc.
- Maintain and monitor CI/CD pipelines using Concourse to build, test & deploy GCP applications
- Developed Junit test cases, mock testing using Mockito framework, ensued 95% pit coverage
- Collaborate with BA, Product Owners, Quality Assurance, and other developers to create technology solutions to meet need

**JULY 2019 – OCTOBER 2021** 

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, PERSISTENT SYSTEM LIMITED** 

#### **EDUCATION**

**JUNE 2019** 

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, WALCHAND INSTITUDE OF TECHNOLOGY SOLAPUR

Specialization: Information Technology, CGPA: 9.80

**JUNE 2016** 

**DIPLOMA, GOVERNMENT POLYTECHINC SOLAPUR** 

Specialization: Information Technology, Percentage: 90.59%

# TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

- Programming Languages: Core Java, Java 8, Reactive Java, Spring Boot, JPA, Kotlin, React JS
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Repository: Git, Bitbucket, SVN
- Tracking Tool: Jira
- CI/CD Pipeline: Concourse, Jenkins
- Software: IntelliJ, STS, IBM Websphere, Deaver, Git Bash
- Basic knowledge about Confluent Kafka, GCP Clouds, Kubernetes, Docker

#### **PROJECTS**

### STC Telecom-Accenture (JULY 2023 – Present)

Developed new microservices using common framework which supports service discovery through Eureka server in which all microservices are registered to support intercommunication.

### Worked primarily on below tasks during development phase:

- Understood the framework and developed new microservices accordingly.
- Developed Kafka producer & consumer APIs to publish and consume the data from topics.
- Used Mono and Flux as part for reactive java programming and web client for intercommunication mechanisms to call other microservice.

### CNA Insurance- Accenture (NOV 2021 – June 2023)

## Worked primarily on below tasks during development phase:

- Develop and integrate new functionality to applications based on business requirements.
- Implemented Microservices &used hibernate for interacting with databases.
- Removed boilerplate code in entities using Lombok dependencies in the Spring Boot application.
- Built Rest APIs using Java, Spring Boot & Kotlin that consumed by 3rd party frontends.
  Developed controllers and services for handling requests using Spring Boot.
- Enhanced logic to enable validations of different coverages of quote processed through API.
- Implemented new CI/CD pipelines using Concourse to build, test & deploy GCP applications, also followed git flow to develop pipelines.

# **MPVS & UPDESCO (OCT 2019 – OCT 2021)**

Digitization of gazettes, proceeding books & newspaper clippings till 14th Vidhansabha using OCR, component management system. The annotated data is now searchable on Vidhan Sabha portal.

#### Worked primarily on below tasks during development phase:

- Developed WMS software facilitating features of multiple user roles for annotation purpose.
- Development of Rest APIs required for EPAPER using Spring Boot.
- Development of backend scripts which are required for OCR and different DB & FS operations.
- Developed EPAPER and WMS software facilitating features.
- Interaction with VS officials for requirement gathering.
- Handling database operations and report generation. Application set up on AWS cloud for making it available for annotators. Also provided support to the same application parallelly.

# **ACTIVITIES**

- Received Skills Star Award in the Individual category in Accenture for consistently applying New IT Skills for impactful business outcomes and demonstrating exemplary innovation and passion.
- Received Apex Award for exemplary performance, outstanding commitment, and excellence.
- Received **Spot Award** from client for great work.
- Received recognition (Lead with excellence, confidence, and humility) for outstanding efforts in the API and CNAC team.
- Received recognition (Demonstrate Core values and Client Value Creation) from leads for outstanding efforts in the API team. Received recognition (Leadership Essentials) for Delivering assignments and making sure release activities are on time.
- Awarded Bravo individual as well as team award for exceptional performance (Persistent Systems).
- Received client, team as well as manager's appreciation for delivering the products on time.

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

- Self-Motivated
- Leadership & Teamwork
- Creative & critical thinking

- Flexibility & adaptability
- Effective communication skills
- Passionate to learn new things.